Hi there, welcome back.
The first conversation you have with your player
can set the trajectory for the entire program.
How do you make it count?
The goal is to establish a clear and committed partnership
from day one in what we call the commitment meeting.
Now this isn't a typical check-in,
it's a dedicated session to align on expectations,
define success and agree on support.
Too often, development programs fail
because of misalignment in expectations.
This meeting prevents that and is the first step
in activating the manager multiplier effect.
And finally, this meeting empowers you to agree on support.
This is a two-way street first.
Ask your player, what do you need for me
to be successful in this program?
A critical form of support is helping them
make sure they have the time to invest
and they make it a priority.
You could offer help with protecting that space
within their work schedule.
Then tell them what you need from them,
such as proactively sharing their insights from the course.
Your play this week is simple but non-negotiable.
Schedule and hold the commitment meeting.
Use the agenda in your playbook to guide the conversation.
During your commitment meeting,
your player may seem hesitant to share their goals.
How do you apply the principles of psychological safety
to encourage them to open up without applying pressure?
Your playbook contains the first conversation guide
with key questions and prompts
to help you navigate this exact scenario.
Review it before your meeting to ensure you're prepared
to build that foundation of trust.
This concludes lesson one.
In our next lesson, we will begin the deep work
of defining your own M.V.P. plus V blueprint.
You've got this.
Now, make it happen.